We're here with Nadya again, and
我们现在再次有请 Nadya
we're going to talk about the stages of design sprint.
我们将讨论设计冲刺分为几个阶段
But let's first talk about what is a design sprint?
但首先我们先来谈一谈什么是设计冲刺
>> Well that's a great question.
这个问题很好
Design sprints started at Google about five years ago, and since
设计冲刺五年前起源于 Google
then have become a powerful movement that helps product teams at Google,
自此 这种强有力的活动 帮助 Google 产品团队
our developers and companies in the industry, solve design problems quickly.
行业开发商和公司快速解决设计问题
>> And what are the stages of a design sprint?
设计冲刺分为哪几个阶段呢？
>> So a design sprint always starts in the planning stage.
设计冲刺一开始是计划阶段
That's potentially the most important one.
这可能是最重要的一个阶段
The design sprint is run by a person called a sprint master.
设计冲刺是由冲刺总管总体负责的
We found that sprints that have a designated person who's in charge of
我们发现 如果为冲刺指定一名负责人
the event, and in charge of the team lead to much higher satisfaction and
可以带领整个团队达到更高的满意度
to be much higher deliverables.
得到更高水平的交付产品
So we always want to have a point person who is organizing.
所以我们都会指定某个人来组织这个活动
This could be the PM on your team, or this could be your CEO, this could be
可以是团队的项目经理 可以是你的 CEO
the designer, or it could be you, regardless of whatever role you play.
可以是设计师 也可以是你自己 无论你扮演什么角色
The role of the sprint master is first to identify the challenge that the team
冲刺总管的作用首先是确认
should be solving.
团队应该解决的挑战
If that is not clear, it's very hard for anyone to make progress.
如果这个问题不弄清楚 那大家很难前进
Second, the role of the sprint master is to assemble the team.
第二 冲刺总管还要集结这个团队
We want to invite all the right talent, and that's the most important part.
我们需要请到合适的人才 这是最重要的一部分
If you don't have a team, the sprint doesn't really happen.
如果你没有团队 那冲刺也无法真正进行
One of the benefits of the sprints is that you don't always have
但是冲刺有一个优点 你不一定拥有你想要的所有人才
all the talent that you want, but you can get them.
但是你可以让他们参与进来
Because the sprints are short,
因为冲刺是很短的过程
you can invite people who are not from your team.
你可以邀请你团队以外的人
So for example, if you and I are running a sprint, and we didn't have a designer
比如说 如果你和我在进行冲刺 我们没有设计师或者研究员
or researcher, we could ask one of our colleagues who is in another team or
我们可以让另一个团队的同事或者是另外一个公司的人
another company, to join us for two to five days.
加入我们工作两至五天
No one wakes up in the morning hoping to have a boring day.
没有人一早醒来盼望着今天很无聊的
And when you invite them on a sprint, they usually say yes.
你邀请他们参加冲刺的话 他们大部分时间都会说好
And they have fun, and they help you solve something quickly, and
他们工作得很有趣 然后帮助你快速地解决某些问题
really benefit your team.
给你的团队带来好处
>> And what are the next stages after planning?
计划之后的下一个阶段是什么？
>> Okay, so the design sprint framework is based on the understanding of design
设计冲刺的框架是以对设计思维的理解
thinking.
作为基础的
So anyone who is a designer might find these things familiar and
所以设计师会觉得这些东西很熟悉
very comfortable to practice.
实践起来很容易
The good news is that if you've never practiced design, this is very,
好消息是即便你没有实践过设计这个过程
very easy to learn.
学起来也是非常非常容易的
Generally, there's six problem-solving stages of design sprints.
一般来说 设计冲刺分为六个解决问题的阶段
The first is designing the challenge.
首先是设计挑战
You have to do that.
你必须要做这个
Once you have done with that,
完成这个之后
you start six problem-solving ways of attacking this challenge.
就要通过六个解决问题的阶段解决这个挑战
The first is to understand.
首先是理解
Understanding a challenge is very, very important.
理解挑战是非常非常重要的
There's a great quote that I love that says, first seek to understand,
我经常引用的一句话是 先理解
then to be understood.
再让别人理解
Many teams fail because they start attacking their
很多团队失败的原因 就是他们根据心中的解决方案
products based on the solutions that they have in their heads.
来设计产品
And they do not understand the customer, the requirements and
他们不了解客户 不了解要求
technology that they have.
不了解他们有的技术
So what you recommend in sprint is to start with lightning talks.
所以建议 在冲刺一开始 先进行闪电式的演讲
You quickly want to hear from everybody in the team that can represent
你可以快速地听取团队中所有人的意见
a particular perspective, and generally the most useful are three.
他们都代表了自己独特的角度 一般来说 有三点是最有用的
First, you want to hear about the business goals.
首先 你想要听关于业务目标的内容
We believe that good design is good business.
我们相信好的设计是好的业务
And we always invite the stakeholders of the business to
我们经常会邀请业务利益相关者
tell us about their objectives.
来告诉我们他们的目标
In a startup, that may be the CEO of the company, or
对创业公司来说 可能就是公司 CEO
it could be someone who's really in charge of revenue.
或者是负责收益的某个人
>> Right.
是的
>> It's useful to have them there.
把他们请来是非常有用的
They can bring valuable perspective so
他们会带来有价值的角度观点
that the designers are not running away from the goals of the company.
这样设计师不会偏离公司的目标
Second, we want to hear from the engineers.
第二 我们需要听工程师的意见
Designers and engineers go together like peanut butter and jelly.
设计师和工程师就像是密不可分的一对
You need them in the room, because, if the designers create something that
你需要他们在一起 因为 当设计师创造了什么
the engineers cannot deliver, it sort of doesn't matter.
工程师无法实现的东西 那就没有任何意义了
So the engineers are there to tell us what is feasible right now,
工程师应该在同一个地方 告诉我们什么是可行的
what is the code able to achieve?
我们能实现哪些代码
And what are they able to do, sort of, within the parameters of this print?
他们在冲刺的参数内能够做成什么样子？
So this is a business stakeholder's technology, what's missing?
这是业务利益相关者的技术 还有什么呢？
Well, you can create a startup, but
你可以创造创业公司
you cannot create an audience if you don't have a perspective of the user.
但你不能创造用户群 如果你没有一个用户的视角
So what's really important is to bring a perspective
所以 很重要的是
that tells the sort of potential users of the product that we have.
考虑我们的产品的潜在用户是谁
A lot of companies are not sure of who their perspective user is, so
很多公司不是很确定他们的用户是谁
it's useful to invite the first kind of ideas that you have about
所以你需要邀请你直观上觉得
who might this be impacting.
可能会受到影响的那些用户
And if you're not sure, you can invite different groups.
如果你不太确定 你可以邀请不同的群体
For example, if you're creating a news app, you can invite people
比如说 你要创建一个新闻应用 你可以邀请
who are news reader and read the New York Times on paper, and
喜欢阅读新闻 喜欢读《纽约时报》这些纸质新闻的人
people who love reading the newspapers on their iPad.
然后邀请喜欢在 iPad 上读新闻的人
And then people who don't read the news at all.
然后是完全不读新闻的人
And by learning what each group needs,
然后了解每组人的需求
you're able to tackle a quite broad set of users.
这样你就能够得到比较宽的用户群
By hearing their opinions in the beginning,
一开始就听听他们的意见
reviewing user research that's relevant, and talking to users directly,
查阅相关的用户研究 直接与用户谈话
the sprint becomes so much more well informed.
会为冲刺提供更为充足的信息
And the chances that they'll miss something are so much lower.
然后缺失什么信息的这种情况更难出现
>> Very cool.
很棒
So we talked about understanding, and we talked about planning before that.
所以我们谈论了理解 在这之前还谈论了计划阶段
What is the next stage?
那下一个阶段是什么？
>> That's a great question.
这个问题很好
The design sprint in the series of intellectual motions that allows us to
设计冲刺是指让你发散思维
open their minds and then focus again.
之后又集中注意力的一系列智力运动
We believe that we shouldn't just jump through solution we should learn as much
我们相信我们不能直接跳到解决方案 而是需要
as possible and then focusing on the best choices and
尽快地学习 着重处理最好的选择
through that we end up with better results.
然后最后得到更好的结果
After the distant phase, which opens everybody's mind, we have another phase,
在发散思维阶段之后 我们进入下一个阶段
which is about definition.
定义阶段
That is the phase that helps the team understand what is the strategy they
这个阶段会帮助团队了解
want to pursue.
他们追求的战略
So, at this stage, we tend to look at the user journey that we want to take
所以 在这个阶段 我们会确认我们想要用户经历的体验旅程
the user on, so, for example, if we're creating an onboarding flow, this may
所以 比如说 我们会创建登录流程
look at the major steps along the way of someone signing up for a new service.
这就可能要设计用户注册新服务的所有主要步骤
Or, if you're creating a new product, this may take you from all the stages
或者 如果你在创造新产品 那就是
that are key to someone learning about your product, discovering it, the first
用户怎么了解你的产品 发现你的产品
time they use it, the first time they return, and what we wish to everyone is
他们第一次使用 第一次重复使用 这些相关问题
that users become their master powerful evangelizers, where they're
我们希望用户会尽力地宣传我们的产品
coming over and over to the product, and they're really enjoying using
然后不断重复使用产品 真正地喜欢我们的产品